Guide to the David Wojnarowicz Papers ca. 1954-1992 MSS 092
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XIII: Objects and Artifacts
  - Subseries A: General Objects and Artifacts
    - Title: "Daxaca" Pin, undated (Folder 092.2.0500)
      Description: Metal pin of human figure dancing & wearing a large hat. Brightly colored.
      Maker: ----
      Where Made: ----
      Dimensions: 4 x 1.5 x inches
    - Title: Turtle Pendant, undated (Folder 092.2.0501)
      Description: Marble-esque pendant "925" engraved on turtle's harness--on belly
      Maker: ---
      Where Made: ---
      Materials: marble?, metal1.5.5
    - Title: 4 Blue Beads, undated (Folder 092.2.0502)
      Description: 4 blue beads in plastic bag
      Materials: ceramic (?)
      Dimensions: 0.15 x 0.15 x 0.15 inches
    - Title: Small stone Head, undated (Folder 092.2.0503)
      Description: Green and white head with chunks missing.
      Materials: stone?
      Dimensions: 0.75 x 0.5 x 0.5 inches
    - Title: Charms "A", undated (Folder 092.2.0504)
      Description: Assorted Metal Charms
    - Title: Fabric Stick in Glass Jar, undated (Folder 092.2.0505)
      Description: Fabric covered stick in glass mason jar
      Materials: glass, fabric
      Dimensions: 9.5 x 5 x 5 inches
    - Title: Multi-colored Beetle in Plastic Box, undated (Folder 092.2.0506)
      Description: Green and orange beetle. "Eudicella Grall: Hubin." In plastic box.
      Materials: Beetle, pins, foam board, plastic box
      Dimensions: 2 x 2.5 x 3.5 inches
    - Title: Scorpion in Green Diamond-cube, undated (Folder 092.2.0507)
      Description: Green "diamond-cube" with dried (real) scorpion inside
      Materials: plastic, scorpion
      Dimensions: 3 x 7 x 7 inches
    - Title: Red Shawl, undated (Folder 092.2.0508)
      Description: Red-fabric shawl with darker red designs
      Materials: cloth
      Dimensions: 33 x 77 inches
    - Title: Two and a half Horseshoes, undated (Folder 092.2.0531)
      Description: 2 full horseshoes and a half a horseshoe
      Materials: Iron, horseshoes?
      Dimensions: 4 x 5inches
    - Title: Horseshoe Magnet Set, undated (Folder 092.2.0532)
      Description: Packages of horseshoe magnets
      Materials: plastic, magnet, metal, paper
      Dimensions: 8 x 5.5 x 0.25 inches
    - Title: Pavement chip, undated (Folder 092.2.0533)
      Description: Piece of pavement chip with black paint, round circle in white "1:12" written in pencil
      Materials: Pavement, paint, pencil
      Dimensions: 4.5 x 4.75 x 0.15 inches
    - Title: Bag of syringes & Adrenaline, undated (Folder 092.2.0534)
      Description: Plastic bag of syringes and adrenaline.
      Materials: syringes, adrenaline chloride solution
      Dimensions: 9 x 5 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Money House 1, undated (Folder 092.2.0535)
      Description: 1 of three houses--largest--All nest together. Originally shown at P.P.O.W date unknown. Included in original inventory by MR (4/28/1995) "B-2"
      Materials: cardboard, paper
      Dimensions: 17.25 x 14 x 16.75 inches
    - Title: Money House 2, undated (Folder 092.2.0536)
      Description: 1 pf 3 houses-medium-- All nest together. Originally shown at P.P.O.W, date unknown. Included in original inventory by MR (4/28/1995) "B-2"
      Dimensions: 12 x 11 x 12 inches
    - Title: Money House 3, undated (Folder 092.2.0537)
      Description: 1 of 3 houses--all nest together--originally shown at P.P.O.W., date unknown. Included in original inventory by MR (4/28/1995) "B-2"
    - Title: Small Monkey Skull, undated (Folder 092.2.0538)
      Description: Small monkey skull with "#413" written in pencil on bottom
      Materials: skull
      Dimensions: 2.5 x 2 x 4.5 inches
    - Title: Coffin with Child Skeleton, undated (Folder 092.2.0539)
      Description: B-65 written in plastic cover--white wood coffin with rose painting, with child skeleton wearing cotton frock. Padded with gold wool blankets and black scarf/shawl & pink towel.
      Materials: wood, wool, cloth, skeleton
      Dimensions: 12 x 11.75 x 38.5 inches
    - Title: Alligator, undated (Folder 092.2.0540)
      Separated Materials Note
      Due to extreme deterioration, Item 092.2.0541 was deaccesioned in Fall of 2008 and is no longer part of the collection.
      Description: Stuffed alligator with rope around its front right leg.
      Materials: alligator
      Dimensions: 7 x 8.5 x 46 inches
    - Title: Stuffed Reptile, undated (Folder 092.2.0541)
      Description: Bleached stuffed alligator. Front legs tied to each other with rope. Back legs tied together with rope. Visible stuff line along the bottom (belly area) and visible stuffing)
      Materials: alligator, rope, stuffing
      Dimensions: 2 x 7.5 x 35 inches
    - Title: Cow skull, undated (Folder 092.2.0542)
      Description: Cow skull found in the desert with worm casings
      Materials: cow skull, worm casings
      Dimensions: 7 x 8 x 18 inches
    - Title: Wolf's head, undated (Folder 092.2.0543)
      Description: Papier-mache mask in shape of wolf's head. Head made of New York City newspapers with AIDS-related headlines visible. Edge of mouth, inside of ears, and edges of eye holes painted red. Teeth made of cardboard, painted white. Mouth is open, large red-painted papier-mache tongue visible.
      Materials: Materials/medium description papier mache, corrugated cardboard, masking tape, paint
      Dimensions: 354 x 495 x 780 inches
  - Subseries B: The "Magic Box"
    - Title: Magic Box, undated; 092.2.0543 (Folder 092.2.0543)
      Description: Wooden box with sliding lid painted in orange and green: Indian River Citrus on top and Florida's Finest Citrus on the front and back. Strip of masking tape on top with Magic Box written in marker.
      Maker: Title Magic Box is in Wojnarowicz's handwriting.
      Materials: pine box, nails, green and orange paint, masking tape.
      Dimensions: 8 x 17 x 12.625 inches
    - Title: Bag of Insects and Bugs, undated; 092.2.0544 (Folder 092.2.0544)
      Description: Unopened plastic bag with sixteen plastic insects and spiders. Paper label on the bag reads: 16 pcs. Insects and Bugs, Ages 13 and up. Made in China, no. 3874, Fishel. Price tag: Cliff's $2.00
      Materials: plastic, paper, cardboard.
      Dimensions: 8.5 x 6 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Cloth Snake, undated; 092.2.0545 (Folder 092.2.0545)
      Description: Green and white striped cloth stuff snake, with embroidered dots of green, purple, red and yellow.
      Materials: cotton, stuffing material, thread.
      Dimensions: 6.375 x 9 x 1.75 inches
    - Title: Small Painted Mammal Skull, undated; 092.2.0546 (Folder 092.2.0546)
      Description: Blue painted sculpted skull with wire attached at the back of the head.
      Materials: unknown sculpted material, wire, blue paint.
      Dimensions: 4 x 2.875 x 2.875 inches
    - Title: Toy Alligator with Feather, undated; 092.2.0547 (Folder 092.2.0547)
      Description: Metal snap toy alligator (red, blue, yellow, orange and black) with brown and white feather attached at the mouth, a match.
      Materials: metal, feather, match.
    - Title: Cross, undated; 092.2.0548 (Folder 092.2.0548)
      Description: Wooden cross with circular shell inlays (14 total), metal figure of crucified Jesus, each inlay appears to have letter (T.A.V.S.?) written in black pigment.
      Materials: wood, mother-of-pearl, bronze, metal nail, unknown pigment on shell, unknown adhesive/glue.
      Dimensions: 7.125 x 3.75 x 1 inches
    - Title: Toy Watch, undated; 092.2.0549 (Folder 092.2.0549)
      Description: Toy watch with green felt strap, gold colored rim and red and gold face, does not work - time set at 10:30, Sat. 25. Image of flying eagle on face, backing of strap is red.
      Where Made: Japan
      Materials: felt, plastic, paper, tin.
      Dimensions: 6.5 x 1.25 x 0.1875 inches
    - Title: Action Figure, undated; 092.2.0550 (Folder 092.2.0550)
      Description: Yellow and pink male action figure with moveable joints, brown hair.
      Materials: metal screws, plastic.
      Dimensions: 4 x 1.5 x 0.75 inches
    - Title: Catholic Prayer Piece, undated; 092.2.0551 (Folder 092.2.0551)
      Description: Christian oval prayer peice with red plastic threaded around the border. In the center is a paper oval, on one side is the image of Christ with text: "Apostleship of Prayer, League of the Sacred Heart." Reverse side is image of a heart wrapped in thorns and cross in flames with text: "Cease, the Heart of Jesus is with me. Sacred Heart of Jesus, Thy Kingdom Come." Copyright mark: Apostleship of Prayer, 1939.
      Where Made: none
      Materials: plastic and paper.
      Dimensions: 2.125 x 1.75 x 0.25 inches
    - Title: Miniature Globe, undated; 092.2.0552 (Folder 092.2.0552)
      Description: Small globe of the earth with unpainted metal rim that allows for globe to rotate.
      Materials: metal, pigment.
      Dimensions: 1.875 x 1.625 inches
    - Title: Miniature Globe Pencil Sharpener, undated; 092.2.0553 (Folder 092.2.0553)
      Description: Small globe of earth, base functions as a pencil sharpener.
      Materials: metal and pigment.
      Dimensions: 2 x 1.5 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Toy Grasshopper, undated; 092.2.0554 (Folder 092.2.0554)
      Description: Green rubber toy grasshopper.
      Materials: rubber.
      Dimensions: 0.75 x 2.125 x 3.5 inches
    - Title: Candle, undated; 092.2.0555 (Folder 092.2.0555)
      Description: Wax candle, blue base with stripes of white, red, blue, yellow and orange; surface of candle is decorated with gold stamps of flowers and leaves, cut away in a repeating pattern.
      Materials: wax, string, ribbon
      Dimensions: 4.5 x 1 x 1 inches
    - Title: Standing Male Statuette, undated; 092.2.0556 (Folder 092.2.0556)
      Description: Wooden statue standing male figure holding a wood staff, wearing robes, holding a silver-rimmed medallion to his chest, likely a religious figure.
      Where Made: Italy
      Dimensions: 8.125 x 2.75 x 2.25 inches
    - Title: Snowman Figurine, undated; 092.2.0557 (Folder 092.2.0557)
      Description: Figure of snowman, covered in white glitter, wearing a red and white striped scarf, a black plastic top hat, and orange carrot-shaped nose.
      Materials: plastic, flocked plastic, glitter, glue, synthetic fabric.
      Dimensions: 3.75 x 2.75 x 2.25 inches
    - Title: Small Buddha Statue, undated; 092.2.0558 (Folder 092.2.0558)
      Description: Seated Buddha figure.
      Where Made: Mexico
      Materials: possibly ceramic
      Dimensions: 1.5 x 1.75 x 2 inches
    - Title: Bracelet, undated; 092.2.0559 (Folder 092.2.0559)
      Description: Leather bracelet studded with silver-rimmed red stones.
      Materials: leather, metal, red plastic or ceramic
      Dimensions: 0.75 x 2.5 x 2.5 inches
    - Title: Dog-head Toy, undated; 092.2.0560 (Folder 092.2.0560)
      Description: Plastic dog head attached to rubber base, perhaps a horn.
      Maker: Toho Brand
      Materials: plastic, rubber
      Dimensions: 3.75 x 1.125 x 1.8 inches
    - Title: Small Embroidered Snap Purse, undated; 092.2.0561 (Folder 092.2.0561)
      Description: Cloth purse: turquoise with green, pink, black embroidery of foliage, figurines and pagodas in Chinese style, black cloth lining. Gold sticker on inside flap: Joan Good, Jewelry, 809 Royal Street, New Orleans.
      Materials: synthetic cloth, metal, paper, thread
      Dimensions: 2.375 x 4.25 x 0.375 inches
    - Title: Framed Photo of Young Yogi, 1982; 092.2.0562 (Folder 092.2.0562)
      Description: Sepia colored photograph of boy wearing a necklace and large bindi dot on his forehead, framed in plastic standing frame. Boy is probably Swami Muktananda. Copyright SYDA Foundation.
      Maker: SYDA Foundation
      Materials: plastic, photographic paper, sticker adhesive and paper.
      Dimensions: 3.375 x 2.25 x 1.75 inches
    - Title: Box of Rocks and Beads, undated; 092.2.0563 (Folder 092.2.0563)
      Description: Cardboard box labeled by MR: Rock and Beads, Lump Metal (Money New Guinea?). Contains postcard from Subversive Film and Video, Danish Institute Workshop 1992; joker card; red stone in bag labeled by MR: ants in amber?; bag of three turquoise colored beads; bag of five buttons made from Indian head US coins in bag; large turquoise, brown and black bead in bag; two turquoise and brown beads; one cream colored rock; small spherical fossil insect; heavy metal sphere, spherical brown organic matter; grey polyhedral rock; small black and red bead; quartz stone; small faceted teardrop shaped red gem.
      Materials: cardboard, medical tape, paper, metal, various stones (turquoise), tissue paper, plastic bags. Written note on postcard reads: Dear David, here's the magazine I spoke to you about. Call me whenever or I'll call you, your pal Richard.
      Dimensions: 1.375 x 5.125 x 1.375 inches
    - Title: Carved Stone Animal, undated; 092.2.0564 (Folder 092.2.0564)
      Description: Carved stone animal, green with dark grey flecks, flat stone with simple linear carving in low relief - may be a frog.
      Dimensions: 1.25 x 3.125 x 3.375 inches
    - Title: Essential Oil Bottles in Plastic Bag, undated; 092.2.0565 (Folder 092.2.0565)
      Description: Plastic bag containing three small bottles of Devi Puja Oil; bottle 1 Heena, bottle 2 Kus, bottle 3 Majmua. Each bottle is round glass with gold screw top and gold and blue label, each bottle contains varying amounts of oil. Bag is labeled: Ants in Amber.
      Materials: glass, metal, paper, adhesive, essential oil, plastic.
      Dimensions: 4.5 x 3 inches
    - Title: Concrete Chunk, undated; 092.2.0566 (Folder 092.2.0566)
      Description: A chunk of concrete that, on one flat side, has two layers of white concrete and blue paint (with some flecks of yellow and darker blue on the surface).
      Materials: concrete, paint
      Dimensions: 2 x 3.25 x 4.25 inches
    - Title: Envelope of Paper Currency, undated; 092.2.0567 (Folder 092.2.0567)
      Description: Envelope labeled: 280,000 and Argentina Pesos. contents: seven 1 peso bills; eighteen 10,000 peso bills; one 100,000 peso bill; one 100 Turkish bill; one 50 Israeli bill.
      Materials: bank note paper and dye, tape.
      Dimensions: 4 x 9.5 inches
    - Title: Tiny Framed Photo, undated; 092.2.0568 (Folder 092.2.0568)
      Description: Small black and white image of man, with a metallic green border and a metal frame with a looped hook on the back.
      Materials: metal, paper
      Dimensions: 1.4 x 1.125 x 0.125 inches
    - Title: Dried Flowers, undated; 092.2.0569 (Folder 092.2.0569)
      Description: Dried flowers in an empty plastic tape cassette case.
      Materials: flowers (organic material), plastic.
      Dimensions: 2.75 x 4.25 x 0.625 inches
    - Title: Box of Charms and Pin, undated; 092.2.0570 (Folder 092.2.0570)
      Description: Cardboard box lined with light green stuffing, containing: one metal pin of antlered deer with cross on its head; one metal and bone or ivory charm of leaves and acorns; one metal and bone or ivory charm of fox atop a sword of knife.
      Materials: metal, bone or ivory, cardboard, cotton stuffing, tape.
      Dimensions: 0.75 x 1.625 x 2.375 inches
    - Title: Stones and Glass, undated; 092.2.0571 (Folder 092.2.0571)
      Description: Plastic bag containing eight stones and glass in varying shades of greens and blues. Bag labeled by MR: Stones B(28) and A (19).
      Materials: stone and glass
      Dimensions: 3 x 6 x 2.5 inches
    - Title: Quartz Stone, undated; 092.2.0572 (Folder 092.2.0572)
      Description: Clear quartz wrapped in tissue paper labeled by MR: Crystal R(20) 4/12/95
      Dimensions: 4.375 x 1.75 x 1.75 inches
    - Title: Crystals, undated; 092.2.0573 (Folder 092.2.0573)
      Description: Four stones (possibly quartz): one pink, one purple; one clear; one clear quartz embedded in grey stone. All wrapped in tissue paper and marked by MR: crystals A(37) 4/11/94. Each rock is approximately 1" x 1" around.
    - Title: Group of Knives, File, Clipper, Lighter, Tweezers, undated; 092.2.0574 (Folder 092.2.0574)
      Description: One "Space Ship" pocket and jack knife; one black lighter; one nail clipper; two tweezers; one pocket knife/file combo.
      Dimensions: 5 x 5 x 0.5 inches
    - Title: Toy Trains, undated; 092.2.0576 (Folder 092.2.0576)
      Description: Toy metal trains set in three parts - an engine, and open bed car, and en enclosed car - each with moving wheels. Engine has NORD embossed on side. Set is wrapped in tissue labeled by MR: trains, A(36), 4/11/95.
      Where Made: France
      Dimensions: 1.25 x 4.625 x 0.625 inches
    - Title: Red Stones, undated; 092.2.0577 (Folder 092.2.0577)
      Description: Seven polished stones in varying shades of reds and browns. In plastic bag labeled by MR: Stones B(21) 4/13/95.
      Dimensions: 5.625 x 1.5 x 0.75 inches
    - Title: Clear Quartz Stone, undated; 092.2.0578 (Folder 092.2.0578)
      Description: Polished and cut quartz stone, clear, wrapped in tissue labeled by MR: Crystal B(19) 4/12/95.
      Materials: stone, perhaps quartz
      Dimensions: 4.75 x 2.875 x 2.375 inches
    - Title: Group figurines, Stamp and Razor Blades, undated; 092.2.0579 (Folder 092.2.0579)
      Description: One plastic cowboy; one black and green plastic fly; one rubber stamp with American flag; one green alligator, ceramic; one black plastic cowboy; one white, orange and green alien-skeleton with plastic shooter; one box of Gem Micromatic Blades for US Armed Forces containing two blades. All wrapped in tissue and labeled by MR: Figurines, Toys, Flag Stamp and Razor Blades B(37) - B (43) 4/14/1995.
      Materials: plastic, metal, wood, ceramic
    - Title: Stones, undated; 092.2.0580 (Folder 092.2.0580)
      Description: Five Stones, in varying shades of browns, orange and pinks, in plastic bag labeled by MR: Stones B(29) 4/13/95.
      Dimensions: 1.25 x 5 x 1 inches
    - Title: Face Pin, undated; 092.2.0581 (Folder 092.2.0581)
      Description: Grey molded face pin with pink triangle carved and painted on forehead; two metal rings are embedded in the mouth. Wrapped in paper labeled by MR: Face Pin (by DW?) B(8) 4/12/95.
      Materials: metal, unknown material (clay or ceramic), paint.
      Dimensions: 2.25 x 1.5 x 1 inches
    - Title: Plastic Box of Dried Flowers, Shells and Stones, undated; 092.2.0582 (Folder 092.2.0582)
      Description: Plastic box of dried flowers, feather, tiny shells, stones, box labeled by MR: A(33) 4/11/95.
      Materials: plastic, shell, stone, feather, dried flowers
      Dimensions: 0.75 x 2 x2 inches
    - Title: Box of Rings, undated; 092.2.0583 (Folder 092.2.0583)
      Description: Plastic box of four rings: one ring is gold-colored with a dinosaur image in black and yellow; one dark worn metal with upright piece on top; one gold-colored plastic with green plastic "stone;" one dark metal with dragon design and turquoise stone.
      Materials: metal, plastic, foam, turquoise stone.
      Dimensions: 1.25 x 1.5 x 1.5 inches
    - Title: Kachina Charms, undated; 092.2.0584 (Folder 092.2.0584)
      Description: Two plastic bags of metal Kachina charms, gold metal, labeled by MR: 48 Kachina Charms B(15) 4/12/95.
      Dimensions: 2.5 x 2 x 0.5 inches
    - Title: Bag of Seeds, undated; 092.2.0585 (Folder 092.2.0585)
      Description: Plastic bag of seeds (labeled by MR "Seeds A(27) 4/11/95"
      Materials: seeds, plastic, paper
      Dimensions: 2.75 x 6.5 x 0.5 inches
    - Title: Bag of Charms and Chains, undated; 092.2.0587 (Folder 092.2.0587)
      Description: Plastic bag of many charms and chains labeled by MR: Charms A(52) and B(11) 4/11/95. Two silver necklace chains, one silver bracelet. One silver bracelet with charms. Loose silver charms: four smiling skull charms; cow, windmill, raccoon with New Orleans tag, chicken, elephant, elk, giraffe, kangaroo, jackalope, boar with New Orleans tags, swinging monkey, tiger with New Orleans tag, fly, bag of money with Cascade Caverns tag, crawling baby, pair of dice, handgun with New Mexico tag, kinetic clown, hand in handcuff, anchor, sphinx, man wrapped around lamppost, hut and palm tree, truck, ship, aircraft carrier, St. Hubert medallion, Mickey Mouse, Minnie Mouse, Donald Duck, Goofy, three see no evil monkeys in bag. Loose silver charm tags: two New York World's Fair flags, New York flag, New Mexico, Trees of Mystery, Grand Canyon, Colorado. Copper kneeling man charm. Three empty gun shells. Flattened coin ""Marsh's Free Museum Long Beach with image of human-crocodile hybrid named Jake. Blank paper tag. Silver jewelry ring. Earring ear wire.
      Dimensions: 4.5 x 2.75 x 0.5 inches
    - Title: Stone, undated; 092.2.0586 (Folder 092.2.0586)
      Description: Grey stone with white bands wrapped in plastic, labeled by MR: stone B(30) 4/13/95).
      Dimensions: 1.75 x 3 x 2.75 inches
    - Title: Stone, undated; 092.2.0588 (Folder 092.2.0588)
      Description: Grey stone, wrapped in tissue and labeled by MR: stone A(15) 4/11/95.
      Dimensions: 31.5 x 1.25 inches
    - Title: Glass Phial with Porcupine Quills, undated; 092.2.0589 (Folder 092.2.0589)
      Description: Plastic bag containing round glass bottle with many plastic hedgehog or porcupine quills. Bag is labeled by MR: Glass phial w special toothpicks 4/11/95).
      Materials: glass, porcupine or hedgehog quills
      Dimensions: 2.625 x 11 inches
    - Title: Charms, undated; 092.2.0590 (Folder 092.2.0590)
      Description: Two metal charms in a cardboard jewelry box: one a figure of a man seated with animal on one side and a meditating Buddha on other, with unknown writing; one standing figure. Box labeled by MR: Charms B(14) 4/12/95. Both charms are about 1.5 inches long.
      Dimensions: none given
    - Title: Coins, undated; 092.2.0591 (Folder 092.2.0591)
      Description: Nine coins from various countries: five British West African coins; one flattened US penny; one French coin; one nudie token Heads I Win, Tails You Lose; One unreadable coin. Labeled by MR: Coins A(30) A (31) B (16) 4/11 - 12/95
    - Title: Feather, undated; 092.2.0592 (Folder 092.2.0592)
      Description: Single feather, in tissue, labeled by MR: B(31) 4/13/95
      Materials: organic feather
      Dimensions: 50.5 x 0.1 inches
    - Title: Stones, undated; 092.2.0593 (Folder 092.2.0593)
      Description: Three stones, possibly quartz: two light pink, one clear, between .5 and 1 inches in diameter. MR Labeled: A(17) 4/11/95
    - Title: Stone, undated; 092.2.0594 (Folder 092.2.0594)
      Description: Volcanic stone, grey and red, sponge-like surface. Labeled by MR: A(18) 4/11/95
      Dimensions: 11 x 0.75 inches
    - Title: Plaster Fingertip, undated; 092.2.0595 (Folder 920.2.0595)
      Description: Green and pink painted plaster fingertip on a 1" chain, seemingly cast from an actual finger. MR labeled: Stone on a chain B(10) 4/12/95
      Materials: plaster, metal, paint
      Dimensions: 10.625 x 0.5 inches
    - Title: Worry Beads and Necklaces, undated; 092.2.0596 (Folder 092.2.0596)